many of you will no doubt remember
Lindsey Shepard she was the teaching
assistant in the Department of
Communications at Wilfrid Laurier
University who was subjected to a
three-member panel of inquiry after she
showed a video taken from Canadian
Public Television of me debating the
compelled speech legislation introduced
in federal bills c16 she showed my
discussion with nicolas mat who held the
opposite position here is part of the
discussion in question why don't we do
this let's take a moment we're gonna
explain a few basic things here the
issue of so-called non-traditional
pronouns goes together with
non-traditional gender identities New
York City for example recognizes 31 such
gender expressions in other words
besides man and woman there are 29 other
gender expressions for example Pan
gender queer gender gender fluid
crossdresser by gendered gender blender
and the list goes on and Nicholas this
is where I want to bring you into the
discussion because you teach this you
teach trans studies so if you would give
us a brief primer on so many gender
identities that in your view require non
traditional pronouns basically it's not
correct that there is such a thing as
biological sex and I'm a historian of
medicine I can unpack that for you at
great length if you want but in the
interest of time I won't the
three-member panel included professors
Nathan rambu Kenna her supervisor
Herbert Pimlott in charge of the
master's program and Adria Joel manager
of gendered violence and sexual assault
prevention shepard taped the meeting and
released it publicly producing what I
think was the biggest scandal that ever
enveloped a Canadian University and
certainly the only one in living memory
that became news internationally the
thing is can you shield people from
those ideas am I supposed to comfort
them and make sure that they are
insulated away from this like is that
what the point of this is because to me
that is so against what a university is
about so against it I was not taking
sides I was presenting both arguments so
the thing is about this is
if you're presenting something like this
it you have to think about the kind of
teaching climate that you're creating
and this is actually these arguments are
counter to the Canadian Human Rights
Code ever since I know that you talked
about
c16 ever since this past it is
discriminatory to be targeting someone
due to their gender identity or gender
expression so bringing something like
that up and class not critically and I
understand that you're trying to like it
was critical why I introduced it
critically how so like I said like I
said I it was in the spirit of debate
okay in the spirit of the debate is
slightly different than being like okay
this is this is like a problematic idea
that we won make me wanna unpack but
that's taking sides it's like it's
taking sides for me to be like oh look
at this guy like everything that comes
out his mouth is BS but we're gonna
watch anyway okay so I understand the
position they are coming from and your
positionality but the reality is that it
has created a toxic climate or some of
the students hey you know how many it's
great oh how many okay one yeah it might
be I know I have no concept of of like
how many people complain like what their
complaint was you haven't showed me the
complaint yes I understand that this is
upsetting but there's also confidential
at comfy and confidentiality matters the
number of people special yes although
the university apologized publicly for
its treatment of Shepard as did rambu
Khanna
it is not clear at all that the powers
that be so to speak learned their lesson
and the mistreatment of Shepard not only
continued but arguably intensified so
she decided to press her case legally
and presented a statement of claim
against the three and wilfred laurier
early in the second week of June it
lists in painful detail the many ways
that this situation was mishandled
during and after the initial Inquisition
I also discussed the situation with
Howard Levitt Sheppard's lawyer
I decided that wilfred laurier had
learned very little from its public
embarrassment and that Sheppard's claims
were valid justifiable and necessary
including her statement that her future
lack of employability in academia was
improbable to say the least I've been on
hiring committees and I can tell you
that even than the slightest whiff of
scandal is enough to disqualify a
candidate in consequence not only did I
decide to read and post the entirety of
Shepards claims which I will do in a few
minutes I also decided to launch a claim
of my own against the same defendants I
thought that two lawsuits might make the
point better than one I'll read some of
my claim to after Sheppard's and you can
all make up your own minds about the
suitability of this course of action
Ontario Superior Court of Justice
between Lindsay Sheppard plaintiff and
Nathan rambu canna Adria Jewell Herbert
Pimlott and Wilfred Laurier University
defendants statement of claim to the
defendant a legal proceeding has been
commenced against you by the plaintiff
the claim made against you is set out in
the following pages if you fail to
defend this proceeding judgment may be
given against you in your absence and
without further notice to you to Nathan
rambu Kenna and to Adria jewel and a
Herbert Pimlott and to Wilfrid Laurier
University claim the plaintiff claims
the following against the defendants
individually and cumulatively the
following 500,000 for the tort of
harassment 500,000 for the tort of
intentional infliction of nervous shock
500,000 for the tort of negligence a
hundred thousand for constructive
dismissal aggravated damages in the
amount of 500,000
in the amount of 500 thousand of damages
in the amount of $1,000,000
the plaintiff resides in the town of
Waterloo in the province of Ontario the
defendants Herbert Pimlott and Nathan
rambu canna are professors at the
defendant Wilfrid Laurier University
Pimlott was the coordinator for the
master's program of the University and
rambu khanna at the relevant time was
the professor for the course which
shepard was a teaching assistant for
both had considerable influence over the
plaintiffs employment as a teaching
assistant and status as a master student
the defendant Adria Joel was at all
relevant times acting manager of the
university's diversity and equity office
in charge of gender violence prevention
the defendant University is a creature
of statute created pursuant to the
provisions of the wilfred laurier act
the university is vicariously liable for
all of the conduct of the individual
defendants referred to here in and at
all relevant times created an
environment supporting and facilitating
acquiescing to and implicitly and
sometimes explicitly endorsing that
conduct the constituent statute of the
university the wilfred laurier Act 1973
as amended 2001 and 2016 in providing
the fundamental jurisdiction and
authority for the university to operate
States as its object in Section 4 that
the objects of the university are for
the pursuit of learning through
scholarship teaching and research within
a spirit of free and query and
expression the university has no other
object and no jurisdiction and no
jurisdiction to operate otherwise the
university has no other object and no
jurisdiction to operate otherwise
pursuant to section 5 powers of the
University the Act further states that
the university has all powers necessary
and incidental to the satisfaction and
furtherance of its objects as a
university the Constituent statute
creating and empowering the University
provides it with no other power or
authority Sheppard was at all relevant
times a student in the university
master's program pursuing her master's
degree and employed as a teaching
assistant for a course under
picanha and following that under
professor judith nicholson as a teaching
assistant shepard supported a class
taught by professor rambo kana
she was generally responsible for
teaching two groups of approximately 25
students was assigned topics and was
entitled pursuant to the policies of the
University and of rampoo kana to devise
her own curriculum rambu kana was an
indifferent mentor who had only met with
Shepherd twice about his course and only
then briefly ironically given his
complaint against her as delineated
below he provided her with very limited
direction as to the content to provide
to her students in his classes the topic
for one of her communication classes
held on November 1st 2017 was grammar
she taught three classes that day
Shepherd introduced the topic of the
grammatical correctness of
gender-neutral language in the evolution
of various languages and to facilitate
discussion on the subject showed a few
minute extract from a TV Ontario program
moderated by Stephen bacon consisting of
a debate between professor Jordan
Peterson of the University of Toronto
psychology department and Nicholas Matt
from the University of Toronto's sexual
diversity Studies Program
Peterson and Nicholas Matt were debating
compelled gender pronouns Peterson
argued against being required to use
these new words which he argued had not
developed organically matt took an
opposing position shortly following that
class Rambow khanna ordered her to
attend a meeting the very next day with
himself Pimlott the program coordinator
for the entire master's program and
Adria Joel acting director of the
diversity and equity office both Rambo
cannon and Pimlott had considerable
authority over Shepards fate at the
University apparently so did Joel
Shepherd had never been called into such
a meeting indeed Rambow khanna to that
point had barely acknowledged her
existence at this session all three lamb
basted Shepherd viciously attacking her
personally falsely alleging that there
had been a complaint or complaints about
her tutorial and insisting that in
playing the TV Ontario clip
been threatening to her students rambu
Kanna claimed that are showing this TV
Ontario clip breached the Charter of
Rights and Freedoms and federal bill C
16 which is not even governed
provincially regulated universities
created an unsafe learning environment
and was illegal Shepard was accused of
targeting trans folks even though
Shepard had chosen no side had up till
that point disagreed with what she
understood to be Peterson's perspective
and presented the arguments and the
debate neutrally Ramba Khanna attacked
and slandered Peterson claiming that he
was part of the alt-right and they're
playing a clip of Peterson without first
providing any previous context to the
students was like neutrally playing a
speech by Adolf Hitler Shepard argued
that doing as he asked would be taking
sides and that was not her role she was
then further rebuked for taking that
position at various points during that
almost hour-long vicious and abusive
attack Shepard was reduced to tears
ironically rather than being a
present-day personification of Adolf
Hitler as Rambo Khanna implied Jordan
Peterson has spent decades educating his
students about the evils of the
Holocaust and specifically as part of
his psychological teachings has studied
and taught how individuals degenerate
ethically to the point where they take
place to the point where they take part
in atrocities as part of his
psychological teachings he has studied
and taught how individuals degenerate
ethically to the point where they take
part in atrocities during the meeting
Shepard was effectively attacked as a
protege and supporter of Peterson
Pimlott continued to libel Peterson
explaining that people like him live in
a fantasy world of false conspiracy and
accusing Shepard of being an agent of
those ideas because she had neutrally
shown this video with its opposing
viewpoints rambu kanna falsely but
imaginatively
claimed that Shepard herself was
targeting people based on their gender
identity or gender expression and in
doing so had violated the federal Human
Rights Code of Bill c16
although Shepards conduct was in no way
violative of that or any law Shepard
asked the individual defend
whether her job as a teaching assistant
was to shield her students from debate
and ideas rambu Khanna asserted that it
was and then accused her of targeting
students due to their gender expression
and identity when Shepard pointed out
that she had not taken sides in this
debate the three rebuked her for
creating a toxic climate the three
refused to advise Shepard what the
complaint was or who complained claiming
that even the number of complaints was
confidential as was subsequently
ascertained there had been no complaint
at all Shepard protested that she did
not understand how her teaching methods
constituted any disservice to the
university since the ideas in the video
were already part of social currency
Joel responded without any foundation
accusing her of spreading transphobia
rambu khanna added to jules attack by
essentially comparing her actions to
white supremacy contrary to the
allegations of the defendants at this
meeting Shepard conducted herself at
this seminar precisely as her role
required and singularly represented the
principles of the Wilfred Laurier
University Act for this she was
viciously attacked by Rambo Khanna
Pimlott and jewel they continued to
abuse her even after she began sobbing
accusing Shepard of causing harm to
unnamed students Shepard apologized for
crying during the meeting pleading I am
stressed out because to me this is wrong
so wrong noting that the very spirit of
the university is to challenge ideas
that you already have and reminding them
that she had not taken any side or
position the meeting concluded was
Shepard being advised even after she
promised to show no further videos of
Peterson or anything of the like that
she now had to run all of her seminar
notes past rambu khanna to obtain
specific approval for any future clips
of anyone that she attended to show and
that Rambo Khanna might have to sit in
on her future classes she was prohibited
from showing any further videos finally
they suggested to her that her job might
be in jeopardy the conduct of the
defendants was objectively outrageous
and flagrant they had reckless disregard
for the fact that the foreseeable cons
quences of their conduct would cause
Shepard to suffer emotional stress which
it did
there are various policies of the
University which constitute a contract
between the University and its members
including Shepard article 1.0 one of the
procedures relating to the Prevention of
harassment and discrimination policy 6.1
of the university notes that informal
resolution possibilities as well as
emotional academic and departmental
supports will be explored
none of this occurred it also noted in
article 1.0 two of the procedures
relating to the Prevention of harassment
discrimination policy 6.1 that if the
concern falls outside of this policies
jurisdiction or could be more
appropriately dealt with elsewhere the
individual will be referred to the
appropriate office that also did not
occur under article 3.0 two of policy
6.1 the office of dispute resolution and
support will determine whether a
complaint may go forward article 3.0
four states that the office is available
to provide guidance on the preparation
of a complaint or a response to a
complaint that guidance was not provided
to Shepard article 5.0 one of policy six
point one states that an investigation
may be required when other efforts to
resolve the complaint have not been
successful or not appropriate in the
complaint by Jackson referred to below
no other efforts to resolve the
complaint were considered before
proceeding to the formal investigation
of Shepard article 8.03 of policy six
point one states that wilfred laurier
universities prevention of
discrimination and harassment policy is
not intended to inhibit academic freedom
it was used by rambu khanna Joel and
Pimlott for precisely that purpose
article 8.05 notes that the university
may take disciplinary action against
those who make allegations of harassment
or discrimination which are reckless
malicious or not in good faith although
Pimlott rambu Canon and Joel had acted
recklessly maliciously and in bad faith
and it was ultimately determined by the
university that this meeting never
should have occurred no action has been
taken by the University
against them and Shepard was provided no
protection from their predations the
prevention of harassment discrimination
policy provides an article 1.02 that
each member of the campus community is
responsible for helping to create an
environment that promotes mutual respect
and understanding for the dignity and
rights of others this policy was
violated by rambo khanna Pimlott and
joule the prevention of harassment
discrimination policy defines workplace
harassment in article 2.0 for as
engaging in a course of vexatious
comment or conduct against a worker in
the workplace that is known or ought
reasonably to be known to be unwelcome
or workplace harassment this provision
too was violated by Rambo Khanna Pym law
and jool article 2.07 defines a poisoned
environment as where harassing or
discriminatory behaviors are severe and
or pervasive and cause unreasonable
interference with a person's study or
work environment a poisoned environment
may be created a poisoned work or
learning environment is one that is
intimidating hostile and/or offensive a
poisoned environment can rise even from
a single incident it may be created by
the comments or actions of any person
regardless of his or her status
Rambo Khanna Pimlott and Joel created a
poisoned work environment for Shepard
and thereby breached the university's
contractual obligations to Shepard
article 4.04 states that the university
will take appropriate steps to fairly
investigate respond to allegations of
discrimination and/or harassment in
accordance with the procedures relating
to this policy no such steps were taken
instead Shepard was wrongly attacked by
the members of the administration until
public and alumni outcry forced the
university to retreat from its position
following this meeting being publicized
McClatchy president of the university
was interviewed on the agenda by Steve
Paikin the same show from which the clip
of the debate between dr. Peterson and
Matt was taken she was repeatedly asked
by Paikin whether Shepard had done
anything wrong by showing this clip from
his earlier show McClatchy effectively
defended the conduct of Rambo can
jool and Pimlott she refused to
acknowledge that Shepard had not acted
improperly despite Bacon's continuing to
press her on this Shepard had the
foresight to taper Inquisition when it
began and after outrage from the public
and alumni erupted the president of the
University
Deborah McClatchy and rambu Khanna
issued apologies in RAM Buchanan's
forced apology he continued to lie still
insisting that there had been a
complaint and that he had been doing his
duty by addressing it it was only when
public and alumni outrage grew that
McClatchy was ultimately forced to admit
that what happened to miss Shepherd in
the meeting was shameful and that the
material she showed was entirely
appropriate that was a quote this was
only after an investigator found that
there never had been any complaint
formal or informal and that Rambo conop
in Lodz and Joel's statements to the
contrary were false and deceitful the
university admitted in this statement
from its president that this meeting
never should have happened at all no
formal complaint nor even an informal
concern relative to university policy
had been registered as to the screening
of the video the president only when
besieged acknowledged that these errors
in judgment were compounded by the
misapplication of the university's
policies and procedures the basic
guidelines and best practices on how to
appropriately execute the roles and
responsibilities of staff and faculty
were ignored or not understood the
procedures on how to apply University
policies and under what circumstances
were not followed and that the
institutional failure allowed this to
happen the president noted that as there
was institutional failure the
responsibility ultimately started and
ended with her she further acknowledged
that miss Shepard was targeted with
vitriol by members of the university
McClatchy admitted that Shepard was
involved in absolutely no wrongdoing and
publicly stated that the university was
taking action to ensure that this did
not occur again a claim that was and
remains entirely false Shepard has never
received redress of any kind nor has she
been consulted about the input that this
treatment has had on her and her career
prospects instead
she was subjected to continuing abuse
and a toxic climate from the University
and its representatives as described
below in McLeod she's apology on
November 21st 2017 she states that quote
supports were in place to support
student involvement in a situation who
are targeted with extreme vitriol
through the situation end quote
yet she and the University offered
Shepard no such support in McClatchy
claiming to be troubled by the way quote
everyone end quote involved in the
situation was targeted with extreme
vitriol she showed the same an equal
concern for shepherds predators as for
Shepard herself the president also
acknowledged that the rationale for
invoking the gender and sexual violence
policy did not exist that it was
misapplied and that this was a
significant overreach Shepard relies on
McClatchy admissions here in McLeod she
claimed that quote Laurier is committed
to the abiding principles of freedom of
speech and freedom of expression end
quote
her conduct throughout entirely betrayed
that goal in RAM Buchanan's disingenuous
apology to Shepard on November 21st 2017
he stated open quote while I still
cannot discuss the student concerns
raised about the tutorial end quote
but no student concern had even been
raised about the tutorial
prior to his and his co-defendants
bullying of Shepard he acknowledged that
his meeting with a panel of three people
would be an intimidating situation for
Shepard and would not have invited a
productive discussion Ram Buchanan's
apology claimed that he quote did not do
enough to try to support her Shepard end
quote
when he did absolutely nothing at all
but instead attacked her following the
public outcry the next time Shepard met
with her students the chair of the
department of communications Peter Erica
Hart attended that tutorial and offered
Shepards students but not Shepard
emotional support suggesting that they
would be welcome to go to the campus
Wellness Center he sat at the back of
the room for the entire tutorial
effectively shutting down any discussion
on the issue and undermining Shepards
role in her classroom
Bertha Hart proceeded on
half of the university to publicly
insults Shepard when asked by email by
Maclean's magazine why he appeared in
her class on that day he responded quote
I assume she recorded it why not ask her
for the recording end quote
he then sent McClain's a second email
open quote sorry you're a pro I should
have assumed that you've already heard
that particular recording end quote
using his position of power and
authority over Shepard to intimidate and
embarrass her publicly professor
Alicia's Lewinsky who's Shepard was
taking a master's course from asked in
front of the class for Shepard to put
away her laptop and then said in front
of other masters students that she gave
this instruction because she did not
want to be recorded even when Shepard
assured her that she was not recording
the class further alienating and
creating a toxic environment for Shepard
following these events Ram Buchanan's
course ended and Shepard was assigned to
be the teaching assistant to professor
Judith Nicholson a professor of
communication who had publicly taken a
negative position against Shepard prior
to Shepard being assigned to her before
that semester even started Nicholson had
signed an open letter supporting Pimlott
and rambu Khanna
this made the university assigning
Shepard to her tutelage entirely
inappropriate created a poisoned
environment for Shepard and made it
impossible for her to succeed Shepards
apprehensions about Nicholson's lack of
objectivity toward her were quickly
borne out on three occasions during
their relatively brief dealings
Nicholson without provocation harassed
and abused Shepard and deliberately
created difficulty for her from the
outset of their meeting Nicholson told
Shepard that it was her quote academic
freedom end quote and that no one is
permitted to make the university look
bad implying that Shepard had improperly
done so on the second occasion she sent
out a course syllabus with a territorial
acknowledgement ie a reference to the
Aboriginal tribe which had once been on
the land which wilfred laurier was on
Shepard considering this irrelevant to
the syllabus and a ludicrous act of
political correctness and virtue
signaling
cut out that part of the note and
tweeted it noting that such
acknowledgments were now even on the
syllabus of university courses Nicholson
demanded in front of the other teaching
assistants that she delete her tweet
when Shepard protested that all she was
tweeting was the University logo with
the course name and territorial
acknowledgement Nicholson threatened to
take her to the Dean if she did not
remove it Nicholson also absurdly
claimed that this territorial
acknowledgment was her intellectual
property she proceeded to complain to
the Dean about Shepards tweet in an
attempt to further endanger Shepards
position in the university the Dean
informed Nicholson that the
acknowledgement was not her intellectual
property and called an urgent meeting
with the two departments which Shepard
was associated with the Communication
Studies and the cultural analysis and
social theory departments at least in
part to discuss these issues it was
clear that if Shepard had tweeted
positively about the land acknowledgment
she would not have been in difficulty
with Nicholson the third occasion was in
March 2018 when Shepard needed to
reschedule her last class of the year
and utilize polling software with a link
to available alternate days for her
class to fill out their available
alternate dates when Shepard found times
that all of her students were available
to meet she emailed Nicholson to seek
her approval for the new dates Nicholson
reprimanded her copying two Dean's
claiming falsely that Shepard had moved
these classes without Nicholson's
consent in advance even though the
letter was just such a request and the
request on its face was premise on
Nicholson's consent when Shepard advised
Nicholson that she never had any
intention of changing the date without
Nicholson's approval which was why her
letter explicitly requested that
approval Nicholson counseled Shepards
tutorial entirely this was despite the
fact that alternate dates were available
for Shepard and her students to attend
Nicholson instructed Shepards students
to attend sessions of the other teaching
assistants on dates which were largely
coincident with dates which Shepard and
her students had arranged since this was
to have been Shepards last class she
never saw her students again Ethan
Jackson a transgender activist who has
attacked Shepard throughout the events
here in launched a formal patently
frivolous harassment complaint against
her to which even after Ms Shepard had
completed her coursework at the
University so she would not see Jackson
again the university responded by
proceeding with a formal investigation
despite its inherently vexatious bad
faith and frivolous allegations which
pursuant to the applicable policies the
university should not have proceeded
with Jackson had an online crowdfunding
page seeking a sex change operation
which was initially denied because of
his mental health issues additionally
Jackson was banned from the University
of Waterloo campus in 2013 for
protesting and deep platforming a member
of parliament who was to give a speech
on abortion by dressing up as a giant
vulva and yelling Jackson was invariably
hostile to Shepherd Jackson's
allegations against Shepherd were that a
she was on her telephone during one
class and purportedly disengaged from
participation in that class be miss
Shepherd had made four tweets with
screenshots from Jackson's controversial
social media account sea shepherd
responded to Jackson walking into the
printing room and angrily ordering her
to leave the room and cease using the
communications department printer which
she required for her communications
coursework by referring to him as Petty
and pathetic D when Shepherd and two
others were putting up posters for a
Laurier Society for open inquiry meeting
he claimed that they had followed him
and his calling as they were walking
around the halls and that Shepherds
posters had signage which he found
offensive posters which he acknowledges
removing from the walls without
authorization the complaint of Jackson
was made maliciously after classes were
over for the year at a time when he and
Shepard would not ever be interacting
again since Shepard is not enrolled in
Laurier courses for the following
session despite Jackson's complaint
being inherently self contradictory and
ludicrous the university not only
proceeded to summon Shepherd for an
investigation but threatened her with
repercussions if she disclosed jock
complained to anyone the attacks on
Shepard have rendered her unemployable
in academia resulting in her abandoning
her previous ambitions of obtaining her
PhD or even teaching at a university as
a masters graduate Shepard has suffered
nervous shock as a result of the conduct
of the defendants which was the
foreseeable and intended result in the
alternative
it was the reasonably foreseeable
outcome of their conduct and the
defendants were negligent in their
treatment of her
so that's Shepards claim as I said after
I reviewed this and talked in detail to
Shepards lawyer I concluded that wilfred
laurier had not learned what needed to
be learned and launched a claim of my
own this week it reads in part the
plaintiff that's me
claims against the defendants Nathan
rambu Khanna Herbert Pimlott Adria
Jewell and Wilfred Laurier University
the following 500,000 for defamation
500,000 for injurious falsehood 500,000
in punitive damages prejudgment and
post-judgment interest in accordance
with the Courts of Justice Act costs on
a substantial indemnity basis and such
further and other relief as counsel may
advise and this honorable court may deem
just the plaintiffs claim against rambu
Khanna hemlock Joel and the University
defamatory statements on YouTube on or
about November 2nd 2017 Rambow Khanna
ordered his then teaching assistant
Lindsay Shepard to attend what turned
out to be a disciplinary meeting with
himself Pimlott and jewel to discuss her
having shown an extract from a TV
Ontario program to her students the TV
Ontario programme moderated by Steve
Paikin consisted of a debate between
Peterson and Nicolas Matt at the meeting
on or about November 2nd 2017 rhombic an
app in Lawton Joule each made numerous
defamatory statements about Peterson all
of which the others endorsed both
expressly and implied the meetings
content has since been posted online on
the video-sharing website YouTube and is
available on the Internet where it is
open to the public and easily accessible
by anyone who wishes to view its content
I'm skipping a bit here
at the meeting on or about November 2nd
2017 Ramba can app in law and jewel
falsely and maliciously made numerous
defamatory statements about Peterson
including but not limited to the
following defamatory statements made by
rambu Khanna a Peterson identified
student protesters by posting their
social media accounts for the purpose of
other people bullying and threatening
them all online be Peterson is basically
debating whether or not a trans student
should have rights see
Peterson's position would be the
equivalent of debating whether or not a
student of color should have rights or
should be allowed to be married contrary
to the Charter of Rights and Freedoms D
Peterson has engaged in the targeting of
trans students giving out their personal
information for the purpose of having
them attacked harassed so the death
threats will find them this is something
that Peterson has done to his own
students Peterson has done to other
students e playing a speech by Peterson
is basically like playing a speech by
Hitler F Peterson's opinion is like all
right opinion white supremacists opinion
anti-trans opinion anti-gay opinion
anti-women misogynist opinion G
Peterson's view is whether trans people
are people or not defamatory statements
made by Pimlott Peterson is academically
suspect to say the least he does not
have the substantial academic evidence
to be a credible person B Peterson's
positions don't have credible evidence
just like charles murray with his race
claims of white superiority C Peterson
brings hatred and targets groups D
Peterson exhibits charlatans ISM e P
terse inhabit in terms of research
defamatory statements made by Joel a
Peterson's position is causing harm to
trans students by framing their identity
as invalid or their pronouns as invalid
contrary to the Ontario Human Rights
Code B Peterson is spreading transphobia
now I'm skipping ahead a bit again the
said words in their natural and ordinary
meaning and the connotation of the
comments obvious to any reader were
meant and were understood to mean that
Peterson is comparable to Adolf Hitler
the great
despot in world history deliberately
spreads hatred both generally and in
particular to students is a member of
the alt-right is unfit to be a professor
breaches the code of ethics of his
profession and university is a white
supremacist has and expresses opinions
which are uninformed and uneducated his
sexist is misogynist is racist is
homophobic is transphobic is a
deplorable person is incompetent is a
reprobate lacks integrity lacks the
appropriate ethics to be a psychologist
and professor is a bully and abusive
towards students wants to deprive
minorities of any rights organizes
attacks even death threats on students
breaches Canadian law dehumanizes
certain of his students and lacks
credibility and credentials the
statements made by Ramba khanna Pimlott
and joel infer all of the above
including but not limited to the
Petersons his unsavory sexist misogynist
dangerous racist homophobic transphobic
analogous to adolf hitler and
incompetent in his profession as an
author teacher and professor and were
false and specifically designed to
impugn his reputation these defamatory
statements were malicious and designed
specifically to damage his personal and
professional character as a professor
author lecturer and public intellectual
well you get the picture that's the end
of that I'm hoping that the combination
of the two lawsuits will be enough to
convince careless university professors
and administrators blinded by their own
ideology to be much more circumspect in
their actions and their words we'll see
how that plays out